<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>School Projects on Loraine's Portfolio</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/</link><description>Recent content in School Projects on Loraine's Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Meta-Learning Strategy for Generic AutoML Pipelines.</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/project10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/project10/</guid><description>The field of &lt;strong>Automated Machine Learning (AutoML)&lt;/strong> has been highlighted as one of the main alternatives to finding good solutions for complex machine learning problems. Meta-learning is described as the process of learning from past experiences by applying various learning algorithms to different types of data and thus reducing the time needed to learn new tasks.The objective of this thesis project is to design a meta-learning strategy for generic domains in AutoML.</description></item><item><title>eHealth-KD Challenge 2021</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/project7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/project7/</guid><description>This is the solution presented by the UH-MMM group to the eHealth-KD challenge at IberLEF 2021 at the 3rd Iberian Languages Evaluation Forum.</description></item><item><title>Information Retrieval System</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/project3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/project3/</guid><description>In this project, an Information Retrieval System based on the Vector Information Retrieval Model is implemented. The design of the system is exposed according to each stage of information retrieval and several of its functionalities are implemented.</description></item><item><title>Analysis of Household Dataset</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/project2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/project2/</guid><description>This project uses the data from the UCI Machine Learning Repository, in particular the dataset &amp;ldquo;Individual Household Electric Power Consumption&amp;rdquo;. A real example related to the electricity consumption of a house for 4 years is analyzed.</description></item><item><title>Schizophrenic Classification</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/project1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/project1/</guid><description>The objective of this work is to generate a model that allows distinguishing schizophrenic patients from healthy patients using the visual paradigm of the P300 and applying the discrete transform of wavelets as a method of extracting characteristics.</description></item><item><title>Detection of Negation</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/project5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/project5/</guid><description>The automatic detection of negation and the words they affect is an important task that could benefit other Natural Language Processing tasks such as Information Extraction, Sentiment Analysis, and Question Answering. In the present work, a solution to the negation problem is proposed based on supervised machine learning techniques. The essence is the detection of the negation signals and their scope, all of it in Spanish texts. The work is done in two phases in the first one the signals are identified and in the second the whole scope of these cues is determined.</description></item><item><title>School Projects</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/_index.bn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/posts/school/_index.bn/</guid><description>&lt;p>This section showcases a range of projects developed during my time at university. These projects span various disciplines and reflect the depth of learning, research, and practical application I engaged in throughout my academic journey.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>