<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Probability &amp; Statistics on Loraine's Portfolio</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/tags/probability--statistics/</link><description>Recent content in Probability &amp; Statistics on Loraine's Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/tags/probability--statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DataCamp Projects</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/work/project8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/work/project8/</guid><description>&lt;p>My Collection of Projects at DataCamp. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief description of each project.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="datacamp---data-scientist-with-pythonhttpsappdatacampcomlearncareer-tracksdata-scientist-with-pythonversion6">&lt;a href="https://app.datacamp.com/learn/career-tracks/data-scientist-with-python?version=6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DataCamp - Data Scientist with Python&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="introduction-to-datacamp-projects">Introduction to DataCamp Projects&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This notebook serves as an Introduction to DataCamp Projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Introduces what a Jupyter notebook is, showing how to run code cells.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show how to load and show pandas DataFrames.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show how to show inline matplotlib plots.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show the interactive output of Maps.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="habilities">Habilities&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Data Manipulation&lt;/code>, &lt;code>Data Visualization&lt;/code>, &lt;code>Importing &amp;amp; Cleaning Data&lt;/code>, &lt;code>Case Studies&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="links">Links&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lorainemg/datacamp-projects/tree/main/Introduction%20to%20DataCamp%20Projects" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub Repository&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="investigating-netflix-movies-and-guest-stars-in-the-office">Investigating Netflix Movies and Guest Stars in The Office&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this project I apply the foundational Python skills by manipulating and visualizing movie and TV data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Machine Learning Projects</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/work/project9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/work/project9/</guid><description>&lt;p>My Collection of Projects teaching Machine Learning subject.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief description of every project:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="supervised-classification-and-introduction-to-the-sklearn-tool">Supervised Classification and Introduction to the Sklearn Tool&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The objective of this project is to solve a problem using the algorithms given in the lecture.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>There are positive and negative movie reviews. 1000 of each.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The goal is, given the text of the review, to determine whether the review is positive or negative.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For this, KNN and Naive Bayes will be used and compared.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="habilities">Habilities:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Data Preprocessing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>KNN&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Naive Bayes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Feature Extraction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Model Training&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sentiment Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="decision-trees-and-random-forest">Decision Trees and Random Forest&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To demonstrate the use of Decision Trees and Random Forests, we use the Iris dataset.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Meta-Learning Strategy for Generic AutoML Pipelines.</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project10/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The field of &lt;strong>Automated Machine Learning (AutoML)&lt;/strong> has been highlighted as one of the main alternatives to finding good solutions for complex machine learning problems. Despite the recent success of AutoML, many challenges remain. Learning AutoML is a time-consuming process and can be computationally inefficient. Meta-learning is described as the process of learning from past experiences by applying various learning algorithms to different types of data and thus reducing the time needed to learn new tasks. One of the advantages of meta-learning techniques is that they can serve as efficient support for the AutoML process, learning from previous tasks the best algorithms to solve a certain type of problem. In this way, it is possible to speed up the AutoML process, obtaining better results in the same period of time. The objective of this thesis project is to design a meta-learning strategy for generic domains in machine learning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Analysis of Household Dataset</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project2/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This project uses the data from the UCI Machine Learning Repository, in particular the dataset &amp;ldquo;Individual Household Electric Power Consumption&amp;rdquo;. A real example related to the electricity consumption of a house for 4 years is analyzed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The project is written in R.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A normal population will be generated in which different samples will be extracted and their differences will be studied.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then, we will carry out a hypothesis test of equality of variances between two attributes of the dataset.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In addition, a study of these data will be carried out using regression techniques, which will allow us to determine if there are linear relationships between some of the given variables.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then we will reduce the dimension of the data through principal component analysis (PCA), clusters and classification trees, also making an interpretation of them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finally, we will carry out an analysis of variance or ANOVA to compare the means of a characteristic in several populations.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/projects/school/project2/project2.png">&lt;figcaption>
&lt;h4>Graphic of the correlation matrix between several of the variables analyzed in the data set&lt;/h4>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="skills">&lt;strong>Skills&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clustering&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistical Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PCA Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hypothesis Testing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regression Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Anova Test&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lorainemg/Household-Analysis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Github Link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lorainemg/Household-Analysis/blob/main/Phase1/doc/report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Report 1&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lorainemg/Household-Analysis/blob/main/Phase2/doc/report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Report 2&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/individual&amp;#43;household&amp;#43;electric&amp;#43;power&amp;#43;consumption" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dataset&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Detection of Negation</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project5/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The automatic detection of negation and the words they affect is an important task that could benefit other Natural Language Processing tasks such as Information Extraction, Sentiment Analysis, and Question Answering. In the present work, a solution to the negation problem is proposed based on supervised machine learning techniques. The essence is the detection of the negation signals and their scope, all of it in Spanish texts. The work is done in two phases: in the first one the signals are identified and in the second the whole scope of these cues is determined.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>