<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>School Projects on Loraine's Portfolio</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/</link><description>Recent content in School Projects on Loraine's Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Meta-Learning Strategy for Generic AutoML Pipelines.</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project10/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The field of &lt;strong>Automated Machine Learning (AutoML)&lt;/strong> has been highlighted as one of the main alternatives to finding good solutions for complex machine learning problems. Despite the recent success of AutoML, many challenges remain. Learning AutoML is a time-consuming process and can be computationally inefficient. Meta-learning is described as the process of learning from past experiences by applying various learning algorithms to different types of data and thus reducing the time needed to learn new tasks. One of the advantages of meta-learning techniques is that they can serve as efficient support for the AutoML process, learning from previous tasks the best algorithms to solve a certain type of problem. In this way, it is possible to speed up the AutoML process, obtaining better results in the same period of time. The objective of this thesis project is to design a meta-learning strategy for generic domains in machine learning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eHealth-KD Challenge 2021</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project7/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This is the solution presented by the UH-MMM group to the eHealth-KD challenge at IberLEF 2021.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Two main subtasks for knowledge discovery were defined: entity recognition and relationship extraction.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The evaluation of the task is divided into three scenarios: one corresponding to the detection of entities, one corresponding to the detection of relations between such pair of entities, and the third one corresponding to the extraction of both entities and relationships.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For both subtasks, our proposal makes use of BiLSTM as contextual encoders and Dense layers as the tag decoder architecture of the model.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the challenge, the system ranked fifth in the main scenario, fourth in the scenario evaluating the first task, and fifth in the last scenario.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The score obtained in the relationship extraction task shows that the proposed approach needs to be further explored.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/projects/school/project7/project7.jpg">&lt;figcaption>
&lt;h4>Neural network architecture used in the first subtask&lt;/h4>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h4 id="skills">&lt;strong>Skills&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Scikit-learn&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Named Entity Recognition&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Relation Extraction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Keras&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>NLTK&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Spacy&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Neural Networks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>LSTM&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="resouces">Resouces&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lorainemg/eHealthKD-competition" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub Link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lorainemg/eHealthKD-competition/blob/main/docs/ehealth_paper4.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paper&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://ehealthkd.github.io/2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Challenge Link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Information Retrieval System</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project3/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In this repo, an Information Retrieval System based on the Vector Information Retrieval Model is implemented.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The design of the system is exposed according to each stage of information retrieval and several of its functionalities are implemented.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A visual interface using Streamlit is used.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clustering techniques to group documents and a crawler to gain information are applied.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NLP techniques and different metrics in different collections are applied to check the functionality of the system.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/projects/school/project3/project3.jpg">&lt;figcaption>
&lt;h4>Workflow of an Information Retrieval System&lt;/h4>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h4 id="skills">&lt;strong>Skills&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Machine Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clustering&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Content Filtering&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Streamlit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NLTK&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scikit-Learn&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lorainemg/information-retrieval-system" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub Link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lorainemg/information-retrieval-system/blob/main/doc/C511%20Loraine%20Monteagudo%2C%20Tony%20Raul%20Blanco.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Report&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Analysis of Household Dataset</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project2/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This project uses the data from the UCI Machine Learning Repository, in particular the dataset &amp;ldquo;Individual Household Electric Power Consumption&amp;rdquo;. A real example related to the electricity consumption of a house for 4 years is analyzed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The project is written in R.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A normal population will be generated in which different samples will be extracted and their differences will be studied.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then, we will carry out a hypothesis test of equality of variances between two attributes of the dataset.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In addition, a study of these data will be carried out using regression techniques, which will allow us to determine if there are linear relationships between some of the given variables.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then we will reduce the dimension of the data through principal component analysis (PCA), clusters and classification trees, also making an interpretation of them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finally, we will carry out an analysis of variance or ANOVA to compare the means of a characteristic in several populations.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/projects/school/project2/project2.png">&lt;figcaption>
&lt;h4>Graphic of the correlation matrix between several of the variables analyzed in the data set&lt;/h4>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h4 id="skills">&lt;strong>Skills&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>R&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clustering&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistical Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PCA Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hypothesis Testing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regression Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Anova Test&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lorainemg/Household-Analysis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Github Link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lorainemg/Household-Analysis/blob/main/Phase1/doc/report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Report 1&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lorainemg/Household-Analysis/blob/main/Phase2/doc/report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Report 2&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/individual&amp;#43;household&amp;#43;electric&amp;#43;power&amp;#43;consumption" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dataset&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Schizophrenic Classification</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project1/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Schizophrenia is a psychiatric disorder that affects a large part of the world’s population. Among its symptoms are the inability to process information, mainly in attention tasks and work memory. That is why the use of evoked potentials related to events is a useful tool to support the subjective decision processes of medical specialists.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The objective of this work is to generate a model that allows distinguishing schizophrenic patients from healthy patients using the visual paradigm of the P300 and applying the discrete transform of wavelets as a method of extracting characteristics.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The database used has records of evoked potentials of 54 healthy subjects and 54 patients matched by age and sex.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The discrete wavelet transform was applied with the Daubechies mother wavelet of order 4 and level 5.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>180 characteristics were extracted per subject and SVM was applied as a learning algorithm using cross-validation to obtain a 62.93 % accuracy.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;img src="project1.png" alt="Fourier Transform" style="width:100%;" title="Calculation of the Fast Fourier Transform of the reconstructed signal from the A5 coefficients that represents the Delta band [0.5-4Hz]"/>
&lt;h4 id="skills">&lt;strong>Skills&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Machine Learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SVM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Time-Series Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scikit-Learn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wavelet Transform&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Evoked Potential&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lorainemg/schizophrenic-classification" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub Link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Detection of Negation</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/project5/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The automatic detection of negation and the words they affect is an important task that could benefit other Natural Language Processing tasks such as Information Extraction, Sentiment Analysis, and Question Answering. In the present work, a solution to the negation problem is proposed based on supervised machine learning techniques. The essence is the detection of the negation signals and their scope, all of it in Spanish texts. The work is done in two phases: in the first one the signals are identified and in the second the whole scope of these cues is determined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>School Projects</title><link>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/_index.bn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://lorainemg.github.io/portfolio/projects/school/_index.bn/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>